Grant Jurgensen

Overland Park, Kansas

(913) 940-2213

☑ grant@jurgensen.dev

9 grantjurgensen.com

github.com/gjurgensen

Professional Summary _

Experienced software engineer with a passion for writing safe and correct software. Background in research and formal methods. Proven track record of meaningful contributions to projects ranging from open-source to government-funded research initiatives. Holds a Top Secret security clearance.

Work Experience _____

Computer Scientist

Kestrel Institute Kestrel Technology May 2022 - Present

December 2022 - Present

- Contributed frequently to the open-source ACL2 project, an industrial-strength theorem prover built on Common Lisp.
- Developed and extended high-assurance program transformations for C code and ACL2 specifications that emit formal proofs of equivalence.
- Collaborated on the development, testing, and formal verification of a basic network stack, and its porting to the seL4 microkernel.
- Identified and fixed memory leaks in a large Java codebase, an Air Force mission planning prototype called "SCHARP". Previously, application would reach memory ceiling after 5 minutes of intense workload. After refactoring, it could run indefinitely.
- Created an automated GitLab CI/CD pipeline for the SCHARP project, enabling quick detection of errors and performance regression.

Graduate Research Assistant Undergraduate Research Assistant Undergraduate Teaching Fellow June 2019 - May 2022

June 2018 - May 2019

September 2017 - May 2018

University of Kansas

- Led the development of a prototype attestation manager, written in a dialect of Standard ML. The attestation manager interpreted a domain-specific protocol language and composed system measurements with cryptographic primitives accordingly. Designed for cross-platform support, targeting Linux, macOS, and seL4.
- Designed and modeled a system architecture in support of secure remote attestation. Formalized within the Coq theorem prover and verified several safety and separation properties.

Education

Master of Science in Computer Science

University of Kansas

June 2019 - May 2022

GPA: 3.98

- Awards: Outstanding Master's Researcher in the School of Engineering
- Thesis: A Verified Architecture for Trustworthy Remote Attestation

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

University of Kansas

August 2015 - May 2019

GPA: 3.94

- Honors: Distinction, Honors Program, Dean's Honor Roll
- Minor in Mathematics

Languages and Technologies _____

Programming Languages: Common Lisp, C, Standard ML, Rust, Java, Haskell

Formal Methods: ACL2, Coq, Z3 Other: Git, SVN, Linux, LATEX